COLEMAN SANDERS III

3925 Monroe Street, Bellwood, IL 60104 • (708) 970-6104 • colemansanders111@yahoo.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Skilled Maintenance Technician experienced in performing routine, reparative and preventative maintenance in diverse industries possesses vast knowledge of using hand and power tools, working on electrical systems, components, mechanical equipment and production machinery used in the food industries who is also familiar with hydraulic and pneumatic systems and successful in prioritizing work orders to restore and sustain facility operations while simultaneously managing multiple repair projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Maintenance Technician 6

Tyson Foods Chicago, IL 07/2018-10/2018

- Performed preventive maintenance, trouble shooting, repair and installation of motors, conveyor systems, pneumatic components, values and packing equipment
- Recognized and diagnosed malfunctioning equipment and used the proper hand and power tools (multi-meters, calibers, micrometers, etc) to measure and test equipment.
- Repaired and replaced electrical wiring and components, such as switches, circuit boards, relays, invertors, sensors, lighting fixtures, balances and transformers.
- Performed preventive maintenance, troubleshot, hardwired and made repairs to mechanical equipment and production machines by following schematics and operation manuals
- Used strong mechanical and organizational skills to complete tasks

Maintenance Technician I

Essendant Carol Stream, IL 10/2017-01/2018

- Performed preventive maintenance, trouble shooting, installation and repair
- Walked through inspection of conveyor systems to detect damage and malfunction of belt drives, chain drives, shafts, rollers and motors
- Monitored and inspected daily box erectors, shrink tunnel, pallet wrapper machines to ensure they
 were running properly and performed basic maintenance duties
- Rerouted electrical wiring and entered electrical panel to reset overloaded systems using Arch Blast training
- Obtained operator certification for Power Industrial Vehicles (PIV) Dock Stockers, Order Picker, Taylor Dunn, Walkie Ryder, Fork Lifts, Reach Truck and Sky Jack

Primary Maintenance

McDonalds Corp. Downers Grove, IL 04/2016-08/2017

- Installed, repaired and maintained restaurant grounds and equipment (replaced drive-thru
 intercoms, installed new refrigeration units, replaced old cash registers, etc.)
- Performed basic janitorial duties such as mopping, sweeping and dusting

Assembling Technician

Home Depot West Suburban Stores of IL 02/2016- 05/2017

- Prepared work to be accomplished by studying assembly instructions, blueprint specifications, and parts lists; gathering parts, subassemblies, tools, and materials
- Positioned parts and subassemblies by using templates or reading measurements.
- Resolved assembly problems by altering dimensions to meet specifications; notifying supervisor to obtain additional resources
- Kept equipment operational by completing preventive maintenance requirements; following manufacturer's instructions; troubleshooting malfunctions; calling for repairs

Service Technician

Sears Holding Group

Melrose Park, IL

03/2015-09/2015

- Set up shop, inventory all mechanical equipment needed to be service and repaired for residential and commercial use
- Specialized in removal and replacement of small block and big block two cycle engines which includes the external and internal parts
- Followed all safety, set-up procedures and blueprint specifications, completing all repairs
 notifying supervisor of my decision to allow or deny release of equipment within Sears guidelines
 and rules

Floor Care Technician

Loyola Medical Center

Maywood, IL

06/2013-12/2014

- Performed floor maintenance and operated and maintained all floor equipment
- Carried out all duties that were necessary in resolving reactionary activities, and reported the need for further maintenance and safety to supervising staff
- Carried out detailed evaluation of workshop equipment to ensure that they were in good condition for proper functioning

Plumber

Wal-Moor Inc.

Chicago, IL

08/2004-10/2010

- Installed exterior and interior piping for residences and industrial companies
- Repaired water and sewer lines along with installing pipes
- Rodded all waste lines, water ramming, cleaned and installed storm catch basins and grease traps
- Performed all duties at city and state code requirements

EDUCATION

• ITT Technical Institute

Oak Brook, IL

03/2012-06/2012

Majored in Computer and Electronics Engineering Technology

• College of Du Page

Glen Ellyn, IL

09/2012-04/2013

Majored in Electro Mechanical Maintenance

REFERENCES

• Available upon request